  <page>
    <title>Wiktionary:What Wiktionary is not</title>
    <ns>4</ns>
    <id>12</id>
    <revision>
      <id>87336238</id>
      <parentid>86790977</parentid>
      <timestamp>2025-10-08T18:39:09Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Polomo</username>
        <id>4169049</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor />
      <comment>/* What Wiktionary is not */ add censored anchor (using [[MediaWiki:Gadget-AjaxEdit.js|AjaxEdit]])</comment>
      <origin>87336238</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="11579" sha1="lhmefu5r35hede5blbbbuza3woewffl" xml:space="preserve">{{shortcut|WT:WWIN|WT:WIN|WT:NOT}}
Wiktionary is an online [[dictionary]] and, as a means to that end, also an [[w:online community|online community]]. Therefore, there are certain things that Wiktionary is ''not''.

== What Wiktionary is not ==

#{{anchor|ENCYCLOPEDIC}} Wiktionary is '''not an [[encyclopedia]], a genealogy database, or an atlas'''; that is, it is not an in-depth collection of factual information, or of data about places and people. Encyclopedic information should be placed in our sister project, [[w:Main page|Wikipedia]]. Wiktionary entries are about words. A Wiktionary entry should focus on matters of language and wordsmithing: spelling, pronunciation, etymology, translation, concept, usage, quotations{{,}} and links to related words.
#{{anchor|INCORRECT}} Wiktionary is '''not an [[arbiter]] of what is good English'''; correct English, acceptable English, suitable English, or even grammatical.  This also applies to entries for non-English terms. Wiktionary [[describe]]s usage, it does not [[prescribe]] nor [[proscribe]] it, and adheres only to its [[WT:CFI|criteria for inclusion]], which state that any term or meaning that can be shown to be in sufficiently widespread use may be included. By including or not including a certain term, it by no means accepts or attempts to promote a certain point of view, but is simply documenting, explaining what '''is or was in use''' in English or any other language.
#{{anchor|CRYSTAL|ONEDAY}} Wiktionary is '''not a [[crystal ball]] or a site to promote words you made up'''. Wiktionary does not try to predict which new words will actually achieve use, nor is it for words or terms that you or your friends have  made up. The project has [[WT:CFI|criteria for inclusion]], which usually require verifiable proof of usage over a year.
#{{anchor|NOTPAPER}} Wiktionary is '''[[m:Wiki is not paper|not paper]]'''. It is a digital dictionary. Thus, Wiktionary effectively has no size limits, can include links, can be more timely, etc. It also means that the style and length of writing appropriate for paper may not be appropriate here. There is less need to use abbreviations. There is less need to exclude arguable entries. If enough people support a well-formed entry, then there should be no need to call for its deletion.
#{{anchor|SOAP}} Wiktionary is '''not a [[soapbox]] or a vehicle for [[propaganda]], [[advertising]], and [[showcase|showcasing]]'''. This applies to entries, categories, talk page discussions, templates, [[WT:USER|usernames{{,}} and user pages]].  
# Wiktionary is '''neither a [[w:Mirror (computing)|mirror]] nor a repository of links, images{{,}} or media files'''. Any content added to Wiktionary may be subject to merciless editing or deletion.
# Wiktionary is '''not a free wiki host or webspace provider'''. You may not host your own website at Wiktionary. If you are interested in using the [[wiki]] technology for a collaborative effort on anything other than writing a dictionary of all words in all languages, even if it is just a single page, there are many sites that provide wiki hosting. You can even install [[mw:|Wiktionary's wiki software]] on your server.
... [truncated]