  <page>
    <title>Wiktionary:Public domain sources</title>
    <ns>4</ns>
    <id>44</id>
    <revision>
      <id>86556270</id>
      <parentid>84453755</parentid>
      <timestamp>2025-08-28T22:22:36Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Nicole Sharp</username>
        <id>1000801</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor />
      <comment>/* Webster 1913 */ transposition fix</comment>
      <origin>86556270</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="9699" sha1="rtqauho22fz0uvmcqvv2t0v3rfffd7x" xml:space="preserve">{{shortcut|WT:PDS}}
Using public domain works as a base for Wiktionary: Several public domain works can be used for sourcing texts into Wiktionary. Webster's dictionary from 1913 is available in plain text online, convenient for copying and pasting. The Century Dictionary 1911 is available as DJVU online, and has to be manually retyped. Some volumes of Oxford English Dictionary are available as DJVU and have to be manually retyped. There are some other sources in public domain, such as 1811 Dictionary of the Vulgar Tongue available in plain text.

==Webster 1913==

See also [[Wiktionary:Webster's Dictionary, 1913]]. Many definitions from ''Webster’s New International Dictionary of the English Language'', 1913, have been imported into Wiktionary (probably, as of August 2020, there are no more, or very few, definitions left to import, but the dictionary does also include etymologies, synonyms, and quotations). See also the template {{temp|Webster 1913}}, which is used for all Wiktionary pages that were imported from that dictionary (as of January 2024 there's a lot - [[:Category:Webster 1913|a few thousand]])

Available online for search at [https://www.websters1913.com/ websters1913.com]; available as one huge plain text file from [http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/29765 Project Gutenberg #29765].

For a past discussion from 2002 and 2003, see [[Wiktionary talk:Public domain sources|the talk page]].

==Century 1911==

''The Century Dictionary'', 1911 is a public domain dictionary available as DJVU from [http://www.global-language.com/CENTURY/ www.global-language.com]. It can be read with a DJVU plugin, but also without it in a JPEG version. It is in public domain per its being  published in the United States pre-1924.

==Oxford English Dictionary==

The first [[fascicle]] of the Oxford English Dictionary was published in 1884, and it was published in fascicles until completion in 1928. Oxford English Dictionary is a great source of word history.

Some scanned fascicles of Oxford English Dictionary under the title ''A New English Dictionary on Historical Principles'' by James A. H. Murray can be found at archive.org, as seen in [http://www.archive.org/search.php?query=creator%3A%22James%20A.%20H.%20Murray%22 works by James A. H. Murray]. They have been scanned by a person whose [http://lists.canonical.org/pipermail/kragen-tol/2005-October/000794.html letter of intent] can be seen, as well as his [http://lists.canonical.org/pipermail/kragen-tol/2006-March/000816.html progress] as of March 16 2006. He is scanning those fascicles published in the US before 1924, maybe because in the UK the copyright is [http://answers.google.com/answers/threadview?id=16644 extended to author's life + 70 years]. There seem to be no plain text files converted using OCR.

The volume 1 of OED, 1884, is also available at Fractionary, starting at OED:1_1, and ending at OED:1_1240.

A number of scans are available through a [http://www.openwordbook.org web interface] as of 2012.

The online version is available [http://www.oed.com/loginpage here] using a UK library card number of the correct format (e.g. hertsb123456789).

==Roget's thesaurus 1911==
''Thesaurus of English Words and Phrases'' by Peter Mark Roget is a public domain thesaurus, organized around word clusters. See also {{temp|R:Roget 1911}}.

... [truncated]